Finding Aid for the Ernest Fleischmann Papers LSC.2293
UCLA Library Special Collections
Ernest Fleischmann papers
1935-2010
1990-2010
UCLA Library Special Collections
Fleischmann, Ernest
LSC.2293
41.8 linear feet (98 boxes, 2 half boxes, 3 flat boxes, 1 carton)
Ernest Fleischmann (1924-2010) was a German-born conductor and impresario who ran the Los Angeles Philharmonic from 1969-1998 and helped to elevate it to a world-class symphonic orchestra. He was recognized as an accomplished talent scout, recruiting conductors Esa-Pekka Salonen and Gustavo Dudamel to Los Angeles, and was a driving force behind the building of the Walt Disney Concert Hall and the revitalization of the Hollywood Bowl. Fleishmann also served as a consultant to numerous artistic organizations through his agency, Fleischmann Arts. The collection contains materials spanning from his early career in South Africa and with the London Symphony Orchestra, to his tenure with the Los Angeles Philharmonic and later consulting work. Included are administrative files, consulting files, writings, published articles and speeches, correspondence with musicians and composers, awards, and photographs.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
CONTAINS AUDIO MATERIALS: This collection contains processed audio materials. All requests to access digital materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Stephanie, Jessica, and Martin Fleischmann, 2015 and 2016.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID:9980991723606533
Biography/History
Ernest Fleischmann was born on December 7, 1924 in Frankfurt, Germany. As a boy, his Jewish family immigrated to South Africa, following the rise of Nazism. In 1942, at the age of seventeen, he made his debut as a professional conductor as well as a music critic, conducting numerous performances in South Africa. Fleischmann married architect Elsa Leviseur in 1953, and the marriage eventually ended in divorce.
Fleischmann earned an undergraduate degree in accounting from the University of the Witwatersrand and a degree in music from the University of Cape Town in 1954. He held various jobs in music as a conductor and radio producer in South Africa, from 1948-1959, including organizing music for the Johannesburg Festival in 1957. After rejecting an offer from the Cape Town Symphony Orchestra, Fleischmann became the General Manager of the London Symphony Orchestra (LSO) in 1959. He left the LSO in 1967 and worked for a short time as the European director of CBS Masterworks Records (1967-1969).
In 1969 Fleischmann became Executive Director of the Los Angeles Philharmonic (LA Phil) and General Director of the Hollywood Bowl. In 1988 he was promoted to Executive Vice-President and Managing Director of the Los Angeles Philharmonic Association (LAPA), where he remained until his retirement in 1998. During his tenure, Fleischmann more than doubled the pay for musicians and added a summer season at the Hollywood Bowl. In 1985, Fleischmann was named General Administrator and Artistic Director of the Paris Opera. However, he turned down the post soon after. In 1987, Lillian Disney donated $50 million towards the construction of the Frank Gehry-designed Walt Disney Concert Hall which eventually opened in 2003. Fleischmann was in charge of selecting conductors for the LA Phil and brought in Carlo Maria Giulini as conductor from 1978 to 1985, who was later replaced by André Previn. Previn had an ongoing feud with Fleischmann and left at the end of 1989. Fleischmann hired Finnish conductor Esa-Pekka Salonen in 1992 and helped recruit his successor, Venezuelan Gustavo Dudamel, who became the LA Phil's conductor in 2009.
He retired from LAPA in 1998 after a 29-year tenure. From 1998 to 2003, Fleischmann was the artistic director of the Ojai Music Festival, and also started his own consulting agency for musicians, Fleischmann Arts.
On June 13, 2010, Fleischmann died at the age 85 in Los Angeles. He was survived by his three children, Jessica, Stephanie, and Martin.
Scope and Content
The collection consists primarily of administrative materials related to the lengthy career of former conductor and Executive Director of the Los Angeles Philharmonic, Ernest Fleischmann. Included are a wealth of business papers from his time with the LA Phil including correspondence with musicians and composers, day books, speeches, musical ephemera, and materials relating to his involvement in numerous competitions and recruitments. Also included are files pertaining to his consulting firm, Fleischmann Arts, in which he worked with musical organizations around the world. In addition, the collection contains a small amount of personal materials such as writings, press, awards, and photographs, as well as materials relating to his early life and career in South Africa in the late 1930s to early 1950s.
Organization and Arrangement
This collection has been arranged in the following series:
Series 1: Early life, 1935-1975
Series 2: Los Angeles Philharmonic, 1970-2010
Subseries 2.1: Administrative files, 1988-2010
Subseries 2.2: Correspondence and subject files, 1980-2008
Subseries 2.3: Programming and publicity materials, 1970-2010
Series 3: Fleischmann Arts, 1992-2010
Subseries 3.1: Consultancies and administrative materials, 1992-2008
Subseries 3.2 Ojai Festival, 1996-2007
Subseries 3.3. Colburn Foundation, 1998-2010
Series 4: Writings and personal materials, 1960-2010
Related Material
Oral history with Ernest Fleischman. UCLA Library Special Collections, Center for Oral History interview, 1999-2000. Available at UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, UCLA.
Metadata Rights Declaration
Finding aid description and metadata in this record are licensed under a Creative Commons Public Domain Designation (CC0 1.0 Universal). See LSC's Metadata Rights Statement for more information.
Conductors (Music) -- Archives.; Symphony orchestras -- Administration -- Archives.; Fleischmann, Ernest -- Archives; Los Angeles Philharmonic Orchestra; Fleischmann Arts
- Series 1: Early life, 1935-1975
  Scope and Content
  Contains materials related to the early portion of Fleischmann's life and career, particularly his time in Cape Town and Johannesburg, South Africa (1948-1959), as well as with the London Symphony Orchestra (LSO) in London, England (1959-1967), his brief tenure with CBS Masterworks Records (1967-1969), and the beginning of his time in Los Angeles, California with the Southern California Symphony Orchestra and Hollywood Bowl Association (SCSHBA) in 1969. Also included are materials related to the French government's Commission for the Reform of the Paris Opera, on which he served. Materials include articles written by Fleischmann, correspondence, programs, and newspaper clippings related to concerts and music festivals in South Africa and London, in addition to press about Fleischmann. Also noteworthy are documents related to his resignation from and acceptance of various orchestral positions.
  Organization and Arrangement
  Series arranged chronologically by location.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  SERIES CONTAINS AUDIO MATERIALS: Audio materials in this collection will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
  - South Africa: school documents, 1935-1949 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - South Africa: clippings, 1944-1954 (Box 1, Folder 2-5, 12, 22)
    Contains press written by and about Fleischmann, including the Johannesburg Symphony Post and Cape Times.
  - South Africa: programs, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
  - South Africa: William Shakespeare's Twelfth Night, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
    Includes musical score by Fleischmann.
  - South Africa: Journal Der Musikalischen WettKampfe, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - South Africa: programs, 1950-1955 (Box 1, Folder 11, 13-21, Box 2, Folder 12)
  - South Africa: correspondence, documents, notes, 1950s (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - South Africa: Johannesburg Festival, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 1-6)
    Includes programs, clippings, and final report written by Fleischmann in his role as Director.
  - South Africa: Arts Festival, University of Cape Town, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - South Africa: clippings, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 8, 10, 13)
  - South Africa: correspondence, letters of recommendation, 1950-1959 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - South Africa: Cape Town Municipal Orchestra, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
    One 1/4 inch audiotape of Fleischmann conducting "Amahl and the Night Visitors".
    COLLECTION CONTAINS AUDIO MATERIALS: Audio materials in this collection will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
  - South Africa: radio bulletin, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - LSO: publications and calendars, 1959-1960 (Box 3, Folder 1-2, 4)
  - LSO: clippings, 1960-1963 (Box 3, Folder 5, 7)
  - LSO: letter of resignation, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - LSO: notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - LSO: 60th Anniversary and World Tour, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 10-11)
    Includes travel journal.
  - LSO: Board of Directors meeting minutes, 1964 October 8 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - LSO: press, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 13-14)
    Includes biographical material.
  - LSO: Los Angeles arts, 1965-1967 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - LSO: Barbican Arts Centre, 1965-1973 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Includes report, press releases, and notes.
  - LSO: correspondence, notes, invoices, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - LSO: programs, 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 18-19)
  - LSO: San Francisco Opera, 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - LSO: resignation, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 1, Box 3, Folder 21-22)
    Includes correspondence and clippings.
  - LSO: correspondence and clippings, 1967-1969 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Paris Opera: publications, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Paris Opera: Institute for Research and Coordination in Acoustics/Music (IRCAM), undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Paris Opera: clippings, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Paris Opera: Convention Collective de Travail, RDTLN, 1962-1968 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Paris Opera: orchestration, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Paris Opera: programming, 1968-1970 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Paris Opera: architectural renovation, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Paris Opera: budget, 1968-1970 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Paris Opera: correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Paris Opera: Association Technique Pour L'Etude des Problemes Lyriques et Choreographiques, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Paris Opera: correspondence, invoices, statements, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Paris Opera: correspondence, notes, report, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Paris Opera: general, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Paris Opera: programs, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - CBS: clippings, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - CBS, SCSHBA: correspondence, notes, 1969 January-1969 April (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - SCSHBA: contract, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - SCSHBA: press, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 8, 13)
  - SCSHBA: travel and financial, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - SCSHBA: press releases, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - SCSHBA: correspondence, notes, expense reports, 1969 May-1969 December (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - SCSHBA: correspondence, schedules, 1969-1973 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - SCSHBA: correspondence, agreements, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - SCSHBA: correspondence and clippings, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - SCSHBA: correspondence, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 5-6)
  - SCSHBA: Memphis visit, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - SCSHBA: contract, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - SCSHBA: Grammy Awards, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - SCSHBA: Mayor's Certificate of Appreciation, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - SCSHBA: biographical materials, 1973-1975 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Series 2: Los Angeles Philharmonic, 1970-2010
  This series features a selection of administrative files, correspondence, subject files, publicity materials, and press from Fleischmann's term as Executive Director of the Los Angeles Philharmonic Orchestra (LAPO) from 1969-1998 and Executive Vice-President and Managing Director of the Los Angeles Philharmonic Association (LAPA) from 1988-1998. Much of the material dates from after his official retirement in 1998, and illustrates the scope of his continued involvement in the LA Phil, including serving as artistic consultant and an honorary lifetime member of its board of directors.
  Series arranged alphabetically.
  - Subseries 2.1: Administrative files, 1988-2009
    Subseries contains materials related to the operation of the LA Phil, including board minutes, funding documentation, and memoranda. Also included is a wealth of material leading up to the construction of the Disney Concert Hall in downtown Los Angeles.
    - 2004-2005 Season (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - 2005-2006 Season (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - 2008-2009 Season (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - 25th Anniversary with LAPA, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Artistic consultancy, 1999-2000 (Box 60, Folder 13)
    - Assistant conductors, 1998 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Blue Ribbon Committee, 1998-1999 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Board of Directors, 1998-2009 (Box 17, Folder 1-4, Box 24, Folder 1, Box 23, Folder 7-8, Box 22, Folder 1-3, Box 28, Folder 13, Box 60, Folder 2,11)
    - Brady New Music Fund, 1998-1999 (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - Business and Professional Committee roster, 1998 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Chronological files, 1997-1998 (Box 24, Folder 4-7, Box 25, Folder 1-6)
    - Concert schedules, 1999 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Conductors' itineraries, 1999-2000 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Consulting, 2002 (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - Development, 1999-2002 (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - Distinguished Artists Award, 1997 November-1997 December (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Donations: Hollywood Bowl, 1998 (Box 60, Folder 15)
    - Donations: Winter, 1997-1998 (Box 60, Folder 14)
    - Education, 2008 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Endowment, 1990-2008 (Box 28, Folder 6, Box 92, Folder 1, Box 60, Folder 8, Box 26, Folder 3, Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Financial statements, 2004 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - General correspondence and expense reports, 1998-2007 (Box 26, Folder 5, Box 91, Folder 4)
    - High School Night Campaign, 1985 (Box 85, Folder 11)
    - Historical operating fund, 2000s (Box 85, Folder 12)
    - Hollywood Bowl, 1998-1999 (Box 28, Folder 11, Box 93, Folder 7, Box 91, Folder 10)
    - Los Angeles County, undated (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Los Angeles Philharmonic 2001 and onwards, 1998-2000 (Box 27, Folder 4-6)
    - LAPA, 1986-2001 (Box 60, Folder 12, Box 9, Folder 6, Box 10, Folder 1, Box 13, Folder 4-6, Box 8)
      Scope and Contents
      Includes materials related to André Previn, Esa-Pekka Salonen, and Dorothy Chandler.
    - LAPA: 1990 Season (Box 10, Folder 6)
      Includes material related to Leonard Berstein's memorial.
    - LAPA: 1991 Season, 1991 January-1991 June (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - LAPA: 1994 Season (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - LAPA: 1996 Season, 1996 May-1996 September (Box 12, Folder 6)
      Correspondence, clippings, programs regarding LAPA, Hollywood Bowl, retirement, and honors.
    - LAPA: 1998 Season (Box 14, Folder 4)
      Retirement, "ABCD" score, Disney Concert Hall
    - LAPA archives: 1954-1960 inventory, circa 2000s (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - LAPO: agenda, 2005-2006 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - LAPO: Production schedule, 1999 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Leadership briefing program, 2001 (Box 26, Folder 6-7)
    - Managing Director search, 1999 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Marketing, 1998 (Box 60, Folder 9)
    - Master Agreement: LAPA and Musicians Union (Box 85, Folder unknown container)
    - Memoranda, 1998-1999 (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - Music Center Foundation, 1998 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Music Center: master calendar, 1998-1999 (Box 91, Folder 5)
    - Music Director search: potential, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 11)
      Includes clippings, correspondence, and notes.
    - Music Director search: Esa-Pekka Salonen, 1988-1989 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Notes: Board of Directors, architects interviews, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Phone message book, undated (Box 27, Folder 1-3)
    - Programs judged by Fleischmann, 2000-2008 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Publicity, 2008-2010 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Retirement, 1996 January-1998 (Box 14, Folder 5, Box 12)
    - Rolodex additions, 2007 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Seating charts, undated (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Senior Managers meeting, 1994-1997 (Box 23, Folder 4-6)
    - The Ten, 1988-1998 (Box 23, Folder 1-3)
    - Walt Disney Concert Hall: 2008/2009 Events (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Walt Disney Concert Hall: Cal Arts, 1997 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Walt Disney Concert Hall: Southwest Heights Philharmonic Committee, 1998 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Walt Disney Concert Hall: contributions, 1997-1999 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Walt Disney Concert Hall: County of Los Angeles, 1997-1998 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Walt Disney Concert Hall: Disney I, 1996-2000 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Walt Disney Concert Hall: Dworsky & Associates, 1994 (Box 92, Folder 3)
    - Walt Disney Concert Hall: focus Groups Report, 2005 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Walt Disney Concert Hall: Frank O. Gehry, 1998 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Walt Disney Concert Hall: fundraising, 1996-1999 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Walt Disney Concert Hall: general, 1997-1999 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Walt Disney Concert Hall: guest List, 2010 (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Walt Disney Concert Hall: LAPA, 2003 (Box 34, Folder 13)
    - Walt Disney Concert Hall: November 1998 Initiative (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Walt Disney Concert Hall: opening, 2003 (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Walt Disney Concert Hall: pledges, 1999 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Walt Disney Concert Hall: poster, undated (Box 92, Folder 2)
    - Walt Disney Concert Hall: programming, 1997 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Walt Disney Concert Hall: programming, 1998 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Walt Disney Concert Hall: programs, 1988-1989 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Walt Disney Concert Hall: solicitation Materials, 1998 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Walt Disney Concert Hall: Van Breda Report, 1998 (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Winter Season, 2000 (Box 60, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 2.2: Correspondence and subject files, 1980-2008
    Subseries contains subject files and correspondence pertaining to various orchestras, competitions, venues, and festivals world-wide. Includes material relating to Fleischmann's appointment to, and immediate resignation from, the Paris Opera in November 1985. Also contains materials relating to conductor André Previn's departure and Esa-Pekka Salonen's subsequent contract.
    - Academy Awards, 1997-1998 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Adelaide Symphony Pool, 2002-2003 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - American Academy in Berlin, 1999-2001 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - American Academy in Rome, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - American Classical Music Hall of Fame, 1999-2000 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - American Symphony Orchestra League: Music Director search, 2006 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - American Symphony Orchestra League: reports, 1980-1982 (Box 92, Folder 6)
    - American Youth Symphony, 2001 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Andante, 2002 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Architectural plans, 1990s (Box 100)
      Auditorium Roma, Seventh Regiment Armory Conservancy
    - Artists' Management, 1999-2005 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - ASCO, 1999 (Box 85, Folder 7)
    - Asia-Pacific Orchestra Summit, 1999-2001 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Asia-Pacific Region Orchestras, undated (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - ASOL Millennium Project, 1997-2000 (Box 31, Folder 4-5)
    - Association of Japanese Symphony Orchestras, 1999 (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - "B" correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Besançon Conducting Competition, 2005 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Boston Symphony Orchestra, 1998 (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Boulez, Met Opera, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Cape Town Philharmonic, 1999-2000 (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - Chicago Lyric Opera, 2001 (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - City of Birmingham Symphony Orchestra, 1998-1999 (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - Cleveland Orchestra, 2000-2003 (Box 32, Folder 16)
    - Competitions, 2000-2005 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Composers, assorted, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Concertgebouw, 1999-2002 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Connell, Michael, 1988 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1992-1996 December (Box 11, Folder 3, Box 12, Folder 7)
      Hollywood Bowl, Salonen, personal, medical report
    - Correspondence: retirement, 1998 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence and notes: André Previn, Esa-Pekka Salonen, 1987-1988 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Deutsche Symphonie Orchester Berlin, 1998-2000 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Donatella Flick Conducting Competition, 2000-2001 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Elbphilharmonie - Hamburg, 2004-2007 (Box 29, Folder 2-5)
    - Elgin Symphony Orchestra, 2000 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Esa-Pekka Salonen Commissions Fund, 2008 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - European Orchestras Forum, 2005 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - FAME Committee, 1998 (Box 85, Folder 10)
    - Festival d'Aix-en-Provence, 2003 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Festivals: America, 2002 (Box 32, Folder 17)
    - Festivals: Germany, Austria, 1999-2000 (Box 32, Folder 18)
    - Flanders Festival, undated (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Gilmore Festival, 2000-2005 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Glyndebourne, 2001 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Great Britain, 2000-2004 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Gustav Mahler Foundation, 1999 May-2001 May (Box 30, Folder 8-9)
    - Hanrahan and Meyers, 1998 (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Inside the World of Classical Music, circa 2000s (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - International Sibelius Conducting Competition (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Internationale Stiftung Mozarteum, 2002-2004 (Box 22, Folder 6-8)
    - Israel Philharmonic Orchestra, 2001-2008 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Konzerthaus Dortmund, 2002 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Korean International Music Foundation Competition, 2005 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - KUSC, 2008 (Box 22, Folder 9, Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Leadership Seminar in Artistic Excellence (Aspen), 1999-2000 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Leadership Seminar in Artistic Excellence: feedback, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Lincoln Center, 2004 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - List of composers and orchestras, undated (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - List of pianists, undated (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - London Philharmonic Orchestra, 1995 November 23-1995 December 4 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - London Philharmonic Orchestra, 2000-2002 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - London Symphony Orchestra: consultancy, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - London Symphony Orchestra, 2001-2004 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Long Beach Opera, 2007 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Long Beach Symphony Orchestra, 1999 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Los Angeles Opera, 2002-2003 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Lucerne Festival Academy, 2005-2006 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Major Orchestra Managers, 1985 (Box 85, Folder 13)
    - March of Dimes Gourmet Gala, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Met Opera, Giulini, 1979-1983 (Box 7, Folder 7-12)
    - Milwaukee Symphony Orchestra, 2006 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - "The Mind of the Maestro", 1987 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Minnesota Orchestra, 2002 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Monday Evening Concerts, 2005-2008 (Box 21, Folder 2-3)
    - Monte Carlo Masters, 2007 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Montreal S.O. Competition, 2007 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Music Center, undated (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - NDR Sinfonieorchester, 1999-2006 (Box 21, Folder 5-7)
    - National Endowment for the Arts (NEA), 2003-2004 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - NEA site visits, 2002 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - New York Philharmonic, 1998-2001 (Box 33, Folder 10)